<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Articles to be enquired of by the minister, church-wardens, and sidement of euery parish within the archdeaconrie of London ...</title>
            <author>Church of England. Archdeaconry of London.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1617</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 19 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A00216</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 10268.5</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S3089</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">33142604</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 33142604</idno>
            <idno type="VID">28148</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A00216)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 28148)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1885:10)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Articles to be enquired of by the minister, church-wardens, and sidement of euery parish within the archdeaconrie of London ...</title>
                  <author>Church of England. Archdeaconry of London.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>By T. Purfoot,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1617?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Blank form, dated in ms. at end: 23. day of Septemb. 1617.</note>
                  <note>Imprint suggested by STC (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Society of Antiquaries.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Church of England --  Pastoral letters and charges.</term>
               <term>Visitations, Ecclesiastical --  England.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  London (England) --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2007-08</date>
            <label>Aptara</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="agenda">
            <pb facs="tcp:28148:1"/>
            <head>
               <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g>Articles to be enquired of by the Miniſter, Church-wardens, and Sidemen of euery Pari<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
within the Archdeaconrie of London: And Preſentment to be made by them to Maiſter Archdeacon of London,
or his Officiall, Contayning a particular Anſwere to euery Article.</head>
            <div type="oath">
               <head>The forme of the Oath taken by the Churchwardens and Sidemen.</head>
               <p>YOu ſhall ſweare, that you &amp; euery of you ſhal duly conſider &amp; diligently enquire of theſe Articles giuen you in charge, and that al fauour, hatred, hope, feare,
or any other corrupt affection ſet aſide, you ſhall preſent all and euery ſuch perſon which now is, or lately was in your Pariſh, as haue committed any offence
or default comprized in any of theſe Articles, or which are vehemently ſuſpected or defamed of any ſuch offence or default. Wherein you ſhall deale according
to an vpright conſcience,<note place="margin">Canon.</note> neither preſenting nor ſparing to preſent any perſon contrary to truth. So helpe you God, and his faithfull promiſes in Ieſus Chriſt.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
               <p>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>HETHER haue you in your Church all things requiſite for the common Prayer, and due adminiſtration of the Sacraments, according to his Maieſties Laws
and Canons Eccleſiaſticall lately eſtabliſhed:<note place="margin">Concerning the Church.</note> And namely a faire Bible,<note place="margin">80. 81. 82 83. 84. 70.</note> the booke of common Prayer, lately ordained onely to be vſed? A Font of ſtone ſet vp in the
ancient vſuall place? A decent Communion table ſtanding vpon a frame, with a Carpet of ſilke or ſome other ſéemely ſtuffe, and a faire linnen cloth to lay thereon at the
time of communion? A faire communion Cup with a couer of Siluer? a decent Pulpit with a cloath and Cuſhion for the ſame? a conuenient ſeat to read ſeruice in?
a comely large ſurplice? a ſtrong cheſt for almes for the poore with thrée locks &amp; keyes, and another cheſt for kéeping the Ornaments of the Church and Regiſter booke?
And whether haue you a Regiſter booke in parchment of all Chriſtenings, Weddings, and Burials? and whether is the ſame kept according to the ſaid Canons? and
whether doth your Miniſter vpon euery Sunday read the names of ſuch as haue béen chriſtend, married, or buried the wéeke before?</p>
               <p>2 Whether your Church,<note place="margin">85. 88.</note> Chancell, and Churchyard be kept in good reparatoms aſwell within as without? whether any prophanation be vſed in them, or any man hath incroached
vpon them? And whether your Priſonage or vicarage houſe, and all houſing therevnto belonging, be likewiſe maintained in ſufficient reparations? If not, through whoſe default,
and what is the defect?</p>
               <p>3 Whether haue you a Terrier of all the gleabes,<note place="margin">87.</note> lands, medows, gardens, orchards, houſes, ſtocks, ymplements, Tenements, &amp; portions of Tythes lying within or without your Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh,
which belong vnto your Parſonage or Vicarage, &amp; in whoſe hands, it doth remaine? If not, you ſhall together with your Miniſter make diligent enquirie of all the premiſes, and exhi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bite
with your next preſentment a true note of them in parchment ſubſcribed with your hands, ſpecifying how they are but alled or bounded, &amp; in whoſe occupation at this preſent they are?</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
               <p>4 WHether diuine ſeruice be ſaid in your Church by your Miniſter diſtinctly and reuerently,<note place="margin">Concerning the Miniſter.</note> vppon Sundaies and ſuch holy daies as are appointed to bee obſerued by the booke
of common Prayer,<note place="margin">14. 15. 58.</note> and their Eeues, and vpon Wedneſdaies and Fridaies at conuenient and vſuall times? And whether doth he in miniſtring the ſacraments, ſolemnizing
of matrimonie, viſitation of the ſicke, burying the deade, churching of women, and all other rites and offices of the Church, vſe the formes of prayers preſcribed in the ſaid booke
without any omiſſion or additton? And whether doth he read the booke of Canons once yearely and weare a Surplice according to the ſaid Canon?</p>
               <p>5 Whether doth your Miniſter ſolemnly giue warning to his pariſhioners for the holy cammunion,<note place="margin">22. 64. 67. 84. 66. 26. 27. 28. 29. 62. 63. 68 69. 62. 100.</note> and for all holydaies and faſting daies? And whether doth he viſite the ſicke and ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hort
them to giue to the poore? And whether doth he conferre with recuſants in your Pariſh (if there be any) according to the Canons? And whether doth he admit to the holy communion
any notorious offenders, ſciſmaticks, or ſtrangers: or reiect any, who are not by preſentment or publike ſcandall infamous for ſome notorious crime? And whether doth he admit any
Father to be Godfather to his owne child, or any to be Godfathers &amp; Godmothers which haue not receiued the holy communion, or doth not vſe the ſigne of the croſſe in baptiſme: or doth
baptize in any baſon or other veſtell, and not in the vſuall Font, or doth baptize any children that were not borne within the pariſh? And whether doth he marrie any in any exempt place,
or without banes publiſhed thrée ſeueral Sundaies or holidaies, or without a ſufficient diſpenſation or licence, or without licence in times prohibited, albeit the banes were thrice publiſhed,
or not betwéene the houres of 8. and 12. in the forenoone, or if the parties bee vnder the age of 21. yéeres, before their parents haue ſignified their conſent vnto him, or whether doth he
refuſe to chriſten, or to burie, or doth deferre the ſame longer than he ſhould, and whether by his default any child hath dyed without baptiſme in your pariſh?</p>
               <p>6 Whether doth he preach,<note place="margin">70. 71. 72. 73. 74.</note> miniſter the communion, baptize children, (vnleſſe in caſe of neceſſitie) ſolemnize marriage, or church women in priuate houſes? Or doth kéepe or ſuffer
any Faſtes, Propheſies, Exerciſes, or exerciſmes without lawfull authority: or doth hold or ſuffer any priuate conuenticles contrary to the Canons? And whether doth he frequent
Tauernes, Alehouſes, or any place ſuſpected for incontinency, or doth table or lodge in any ſuch houſe: or is he a common Gameſter at Dice, Cards, Tables, or any other vnlawfull
game, a ſwearer or drunkard, or one that applyeth not himſelfe to his ſtudy, or is otherwiſe offenſiue and ſcandalous to his function and miniſtery, or doth not vſe decency in his apparell,
as by the Canons he is enioyned?</p>
               <p>7 Whether is he continually reſident vpon his benefice, and how long time hath he been abſent) from the ſame? And (in caſe he be lycenced to be abſent whether doth hee cauſe his cure
to be ſufficiently ſupplyed,<note place="margin">45. 46. 47. 74.</note> according to the Canons? And whether (if he be allowed a preacher) doth he preach one ſermon euery Sunday: or (if not ſo allowed) doth procure monthly
ſermons and read homilies? And whether (not being ſo allowed) doth he expound any ſcripture, or ſuffer any man to preach in your Church, whom you haue not well knowne to haue
béen ſufficiently yeeneed, and who hath not firſt ſubſcribed his name, together with the day when he did preach, and who was not ſeverly and decently apparelled?</p>
               <p>8 Whether doth your Preacher and Lecturer read diuine ſeruice,<note place="margin">56. 55.</note> and miniſter the Sacraments twice a yéere at the leaſt in his owne perſon, according to the ſaid Canons? And
whether doth he vſe the forme of Prayer before his Sermons for the Kings moſt excellent Maieſtie, exhorting the people to obedience to his Maieſtie, and other Magiſtrates in au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thoritie
vnder him?</p>
               <p>9 Whether doth your Miniſter on Sundaies &amp; holydaies catechize the youth &amp; ignorant perſons in your pariſh according to the order preſcribed in the booke of common prayer, and ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording
to the ſaid Canons?<note place="margin">59.</note> And whether doth he in the Rogation daies vſe the perambulation of the circuite of the pariſh appointed by law, according to his dutie?</p>
               <p>10 Whether doth he euery ſix moneths denonce in his pariſh Church all ſuch of his pariſh as doe perſeuer in the ſentence of excommunication,<note place="margin">65.</note> not ſeeking to be abſolued? And whether
hath he admitted any ſuch excommunicate perſon to the Communion, or to the church without certificate of his abſolution? And whether doth he or any of your pariſh familiarly frequent
the company of any ſuch excommunicate perſon?</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
               <p>11 WHether any of your pariſhioners doe not cauſe their Children,<note place="margin">Concerning Pariſhioners.</note> Seruants, and Apprentices, to come to their Miniſter vpon Sundaies and holydaies to be inſtructed in the
Catechiſme by him?<note place="margin">59.</note> And whether any of them refuſe to come, or if they come, refuſe to learne thoſe inſtructions ſet forth in the ſaid booke of common prayer? And what bee
the names of them ſo not cauſing, or refuſing?</p>
               <p>12 Whether any of your pariſhioners,<note place="margin">13. 14. 18.</note> or other ſtrangers ſoiourning, lodging, or commonly reſorting to any houſe within your pariſh, aboue 16. yéeres of age, doe wilfully or negligently
abſent themſelues from your pariſh Church, vpon Sundaies or holydaies at morning and euening prayer, or who come very late to church vpon the ſaid dayes, or who depart from church
before ſeruice be finiſhed: Or who doe not reuerently behaue themſelues during the tune of diuine ſeruice, deuoutly knéeling at ſuch times as the generall confeſſion of ſins, the Letany,
the Ten commandements, and all prayers and collects are read: Or who doe vſe any gaining or paſtime abroad, or in any houſe, or doe ſit in the ſtréet, or Churchyard, or in any Tauerne,
or Victualling houſe vpon any of thoſe dayes in the time of diuine ſeruice, or who haue quarrelled, brawled, or vſed violence to any perſon within your Church or Churchyard: Or who
haue vſed filthy &amp; prophane talke, or other rude and immodeſt behauiour?</p>
               <p>13 Whether there be any of or within your pariſh being ſixtéene yéeres of age and vpwards,<note place="margin">21. 22. 28.</note> that doe not receiue the holy Communion in your Church thrice in this yéere at the leaſt,
and chiefly once at Eaſter next: And whether any of your Pariſh doth not deuoutly knéele at the receiuing thereof? And whether doth not your Miniſter receiue it himſelfe on euery
day that he adminiſtreth it to others, and vſe the words of inſtitution at euery time that the bread &amp; wine is adminiſtred? And whether doe your ſelues diligently obſerue your office, in
marking what perſons of or within your pariſh offend againſt this and the next precedent Article, and in due preſenting their names?</p>
               <p>14 Whether any in your pariſh hauing a Preacher to their Parſon, Vicar, or Curate, doe abſent themſelues from his ſermons, and reſort to other places to heare other preachers?
And whether any hauing béen ordayned Prieſt or Deacon hath relinquiſhed the ſame and betaken himſelfe to a courſe of life as a lay man? Or whether any not being in orders, doth o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>penly
read common prayer, or execute any miniſteriall dutie in your church, and what be their names?</p>
               <p>15 Whether there be any that doe publikely or priuately ſpeake againſt the Booke of common Prayer,<note place="margin">4. 6. 10. 57. 9. 10. 100.</note> deprauing the ſame or any thing therein contained: or againſt any of the ſayd
Articles of Religion agréed vpon in Anno. 1562. Or againſt the Kings Royall ſupremacie in cauſes eccleſiaſticall, or againſt any of the rites or ceremonies of the Church of <hi>England:</hi>
Or againſt the gouernement of the ſaid church of <hi>England</hi> vnder the Kings moſt excellent Maieſtie, by Archbiſhops, Biſhops, Deanes, Archdeacons, and other officers in the ſame, af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firming
that the ſame is repugnant to the word of God, and that the ſaid eccleſiaſticall Officers are not lawfully ordayned? Or whether there bee any that be Authors or maintay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners
of ſciſme or frequenters of any priuate conuenticles or méetings: Or that be, or be ſuſpected to be Anabaptiſts, Libertines, Browniſts, of the Family of Loue, or of any other he<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſie
or ſciſme: And what be their names?</p>
               <p>16 Whether doe you know any Schoolemaiſter that doth teach, or Curate that doth read diuine ſeruice within your pariſh, without lycence of his Ordinarie vnder his ſcale? And whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther
doth not ſuch Schoolemaiſter inſtruct his ſchollers in the Catechiſme,<note place="margin">77. 48. 79.</note> and teach them the grounds of Religion, and bring them to Church to heare diuine ſeruice &amp; ſermons, and whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther
is he a common officer or artificer, or any waies reproueable in life? And whether is your pariſh Clarke alſo allowed by the Ordinary? And whether doth your Clarke ſerue more
eures than one? And whether doe they demeane themſelues according to their ſeuerall duties?</p>
               <p>17 How many Midwiues haue you in your pariſh which doe exerciſe that office, how long haue they ſo done, and by what authority? Alſo how many in your pariſh doe practiſe as
Phiſitions or Chyrurgions, how long haue they ſo done, and of what skill are they reputed in their profeſſion?</p>
               <p>18 Whether doe you know any perſons that doe adminiſter the goods of the dead without lawfull authority, or ſuppreſſe the laſt will of the dead, or with-hold any ſtocke of the Church,
or any legacies giuen to godly and charitable vſes:<note place="margin">89.</note> and whether is the Almes of the Church faithfully diſtributed to the vſe of the poore? And whether the late Churchwardens haue
giuen a iuſt accompt according to the Canons?</p>
               <p>19 Whether do you know in your pariſh any common ſwearers,<note place="margin">109.</note> drunkards, blaſphemers, any ſimonicall perſons, or vſurers contrary to the ſtatute 37. of <hi>Henrie</hi> the eight, any witches,
coniurers, ſoothſayers, charmers, fornicators, adulterers, inceſtuous perſons, braulers, common ſlaunderers of their neighbors, raylers, ſcoulds, filthy &amp; laſcimous talkers, ſowers of diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cord
betwéene neighbors, or any that receiue or lodge incontinent perſons, or harbour women with child which be vnmaried, conneying or ſuffering them to go away before they haue made
ſatisfaction to the congregation, or any perſons that are by common ſame noted or vehemently ſuſpected of any of theſe crimes, or that being héertofore ſuſpected, or preſented for any of
theſe faults, haue for that cauſe departed out of your pariſh, and are now returned againe?</p>
               <p>20 Whether there be any perſons within your pariſh that be married within the prohibited degrées of conſanguinity or affinity,<note place="margin">99. 57.</note> or their old wines or huſbands being yet aliue, albeit
diuorced from them, or that being lawfully married, doe liue ſcandalouſly apart, or that were married in times prohibited, or without banes thrée ſeuerall Sundaies or holidaies publiſhed
hauing no ſufficient lycence or diſpenſation for the ſame? And whether there be any that doe communicate, or cauſe their children to be baptized in other Pariſhes abroad, or kepe their
children vnbaptized longer then is conuenient?</p>
               <p>21 Whether any woman deliuered of child in your pariſh, in time conuenient after Childbirth, doe not come to the vſuall place in the Church to giue God thanks, as is appointed by the
booke of common Prayer? And whether doth your Clarke lay a Cuſhion at the ſaid vſuall place? And whether doth your Miniſter admit any thereto, who was begotten with child in
adulterie or fornication, without licence from the Ordinarie?</p>
               <p>22 Whether any Inhabitant within your pariſh doth detaine the Clarks wages, duties for bread and wine, or any other Church duties? Preſent particularly what be their names,
and what and how much thoſe duties be?</p>
               <p>23 Whether any perſon in your pariſh doe exerciſe any Trade, Handicraft, or bodily labour, or doe buy &amp; ſell, or kéepe open ſhoppes or Warehouſes vpon any Sunday or holiday, by
themſelues, their ſeruants or Apprentizes, or haue otherwiſe prophaned the ſaid da<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>es contrary to the orders of the Church of <hi>England?</hi> And whether there be any Inkéepers, Alchouſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kéepers,
or Victuallers, that permit any perſons in their houſes to eate, drinke, or play at any games during the time of diuine ſeruice, or Sermon in the forenoone or afternoone vppon
thoſe dayes?</p>
               <p>24 Whether doe any in your pariſh familiarly frequent the company of excommunicate perſons? And whether doth your Miniſter or any of your pariſh without conſent of the Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nary,
cauſe any to doe penance, or to be cenſured or puniſhed by any Veſtry méetings, or otherwiſe by their owne authority, or do or haue taken any money for any crime or matter puniſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able
by the eccleſiaſticall Law, who haue béene ſo puniſhed, in what manner, and vpon what cauſe?</p>
               <p>25 If any one or more of you do know, or haue heard of any fault enquired of in theſe Articles, or of any other crime, the reformation whereof belongeth to the ſpirituall iuriſdiction,
hapning from the <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                     <desc> _____ </desc>
                  </gap> day of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                     <desc> _____ </desc>
                  </gap> that then you do enforme one another therof,<note place="margin">117.</note> and you ſhall likewiſe preſent the ſame by vertue of your oathes?</p>
               <p>26 The Miniſter of euery pariſh may ioyne in euery preſenment with the Churchwardens and Sidemen, who if they will not preſent, the Miniſter may himſelfe preſent to the ſayd
Archdeacon or his Officiall ſuch faults or crimes aboueſaid, as ſhall be thought to require due reformation?<note place="margin">113.</note>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="charge">
               <p>You are charged to ſpecifie the fault or crime,<note place="margin">118. 128.</note> proper name &amp; ſurname, trade or addition, &amp; place of dwelling of euery perſon preſented. And to bring your firſt generall preſenment vpon all theſe
Articles into Chriſt-church in London, in the forenoone betweene the howers of viij and xj. of the clocke, the. <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                     <desc> _____ </desc>
                  </gap> day of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                     <desc> _____ </desc>
                  </gap> And your laſt generall preſentment on
the Tueſday ſenight immediately enſuing after Eaſter day next, or elſe then and there to appeale perſonally, to ſhew the cauſe of your default therein. Intimating further, that you may (beſides
thoſe generall) preſent offenders, as oft as you ſhall thinke meete, as by the ſaid Canons is preſcribed.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
